http://www.samuseum.sa.gov.au/privacy

For the latest information about COVID-19 please see here.
Members get access to exclusive content Membership
© South Australian Museum 2020 PrivacyCopyrightDisclaimer Cultural Sensitivity Warning Health and safety
National Science Week resources
Museum Cafe & ShopIn response to COVID-19 the Museum Café and Shop are temporarily closed. We wish everyone well during this challenging time
Palaeontology
Biological sciencesOur biological sciences collections encompass a diverse range of fauna, from parasites to whales.
Palaeontology
Mineral SciencesThe South Australian Museum is a global leader in research about opal and copper.
Museum
Collection of InformationAutomatic Logging of InformationWhen you visit our website, the following information is automatically collected:your IP address,the date and time of your visit,the pages you access,the documents you download,the previous referring site you visitedthe type of browser you use, andthe type of device you useThese statistics tell us how our site is being used and helps us improve it to make your visit more enjoyable.This information does not identify you personally. No attempt is made to identify you except in the unlikely event of an investigation, where a law enforcement agency may exercise a warrant to inspect our Internet Service Provider’s logs.Personal InformationWe collect your personal information only when you provide it. This may be to receive specific information, communications, or services from the Museum. The information is securely stored and only forwarded to appropriate staff so they can answer your question, action your request for service, or approve a request made via your email address.We will record your email address under the following circumstances:you send us a message by email;you include your email address in an online form;you subscribe to any of our online documentation, exhibitions or programs;you make a gift to the Museum.It will not be added to any external mailing list or used for any purpose unrelated to your business with the South Australian Museum except at your express consent.Data you give us when you make an online transactionWhen you perform an online transaction, we update our relevant databases and store transaction information to use for future transactions related to your requirements and for audit purposes. Some examples of an online transaction include:Purchase of a productRegistrationsCompletion of an online web-based formSubscription to a web page or documentAccess to this information is restricted to South Australian Museum personnel who need to transact business with you. It is only used for purposes connected to your role as our customer.We may use the data to collate statistics about our customers (such as the nature of research undertaken or home suburb), but any statistics will not contain information that will identify individual customers.Your personal information will not be sold or given away to any other person, company or organisation without your consent. However, we must cooperate fully should a situation arise where we are required by law or legal process to provide information about a customer.All financial information is securely transmitted using standard encryption processes and is PCI compliant.CookiesA cookie is a small file sent to your browser by a website that you visit. The South Australian Museum may use cookies to help you access and use our site and improve the service we offer. They are used to track patterns and customer behaviour and record other information from the website. The use of cookies does not identify you personally.The South Australian Museum website uses Google Analytics and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, derived from the DoubleClick third-party cookie. These cookies allow the Museum to evaluate how visitors use our website and aid us to segment our audience by age range, gender and interests, to improve your online experience.No attempt will be made to merge personally-identifiable information with non-personally identifiable information previously collected, without your express consent.You may set your browser to refuse cookies from any website you visit. If you choose to do so, some aspects of this website may be inaccessible, unusable or function incorrectly. You can also opt-out of Google Analytics using the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.Other Web SitesThis privacy statement only covers the South Australian Museum’s website. It does not apply to other sites, even when we have provided you with a direct link. We recommend that you check the privacy statements of other websites if you are concerned about their privacy policies. Privacy GuidelinesThis privacy statement will be continually reviewed in line with the ongoing development of this Internet site. It is based on national and international privacy standards and follows the guidelines set out in the Federal Government’s Information Privacy Principles Guidelines.For details of your rights to access your own personal information and, where appropriate, to correct such information, view the Freedom of Information Commitment.If you have any questions about our privacy policy please contact us.
Coming up next
Museum
Up Next:Copyright
View
